Smith, Bernard C.; Papers apap279
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Bernard C. Smith Papers
1963-1969
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
apap279
10.4 cubic ft.
The Bernard C. Smith Papers document the first four years of Smith's service as a New York State Senator. While Smith is most well known for his work in conservation, these papers from his early Senate career contain significant materials on the issues of abortion, education (especially for mentally handicapped children), medical treatment and penal codes and laws.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
Bernard C. Smith initially donated his papers to Syracuse University in a series of donations in 1969-1970. In 2006, the papers were transferred to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Biographical Sketch
Bernard C. Smith was born in Barnesboro, Pennsylvania in 1923. World War II interrupted his studies at Cornell University and during the war he served as a lieutenant and platoon commander of a tank battalion in the Pacific Theatre. When Smith returned home he continued his studies at Cornell where he majored in government and law. He subsequently earned his bachelor of arts degree and a law degree. He practiced law for 44 years, in both private practice and the public sector. From 1951-1958 he served as a New York State Assistant District Attorney, obtaining the title of Chief Assistant by 1958. He served as District Attorney of Suffolk County from 1962-1965.
In 1965 voters of the 2nd District (part of Suffolk County), elected Smith, a Republican, to represent them in the New York State Senate. During his early years as a State Senator Smith focused on the debate surrounding the question of whether or not to legalize abortion in New York, on creating legislation that would help provide better educational services for mentally handicapped students, and for revising and updating penal codes and laws in an attempt to deal with crime in the state. Smith also began to introduce legislation to protect the environment, which became the main focus of his work in later years.
By the end of his Senate career in 1978, Smith had chaired the Conservation Committee and helped to found the Adirondack Park Agency and the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation. From 1978-1990 Smith served as the commissioner of the State Investigation Committee.
Smith was married to the former Elizabeth Reynolds for 44 years and they had five children. In 1993 at the age of 70, Smith passed away from an inoperable brain tumor.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains papers from Bernard C. Smith's early career as a State Senator, from 1965-1969. In Series 1, Subject Files, the topics with the largest amount of information are abortion, education (especially special education), medical treatment and penal codes. The abortion files contain a significant number of opinions of New York citizens (in the form of correspondence and formal testimony) at the time New York's abortion laws were being reconsidered. The education files include materials on debates surrounding busing to questions about decentralization and funding. Materials pertaining to medical treatment range from provision of Medicaid to improvement of New York State's mental health resources. The files on penal codes contain information about penal laws and institutions, and there are other related subject files on issues of crime in general.
The Smith Papers contain an abundant amount of Smith's correspondence with his constituents. Researchers who are interested in studying public opinion on issues of abortion, education, medicine, penal law, and environmental protection in the late 1960s will find ample materials in this collection.
While there are materials in Series 1 that relate to environmental conservation, there are no materials that directly pertain to the creation of the Adirondack Park Agency or the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation, which were developed after 1969. There are, however, individual subject files that pertain to certain specific conservation issues such as the Conservation Bill of Rights and regulation of game fishing.
Series 2, Bills, contains files pertaining to each of the bills that Smith introduced in the State Senate in 1968.
Please note that there also are background materials in Series 1 which Smith referenced while a State Senator that date to 1963-1964.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1 - Subject Files, 1963-1969, Undated
Series 2 - Bills, 1967-1968
Series 1 is arranged alphabetically and Series 2 is arranged chronologically by bill number.
Politics and Politicians; Abortion--New York (State); Abortion--New York (State)--Public opinion; Conservation of natural resources--New York (State); Education--New York (State); Special education--Law and legislation--New York (State); Special education--New York (State); Mental health--New York (State); Mental retardation--New York (State); Medicaid--New York (State); Criminal law---New York (State); New York (State)--Politics and government; Bills (legislative records); Clippings; Correspondence; Files by subject; Legislative Records; Photographs; Official reports; Smith, Bernard C.; New York (State). Legislature. Senate; New York (State). Legislature. Senate. Committe on Penal Institutions; New York (State). Legislature. Senate. Committee on Environmental Conservation and Recreation; New York (State). Legislature. Senate. Standing Committee on Insurance; New York (State). Legislature. Senate. Committee on Finance; New York (State). Legislature. Senate. Education Committee; New York (State). Legislature. Senate. Standing Committee on Codes; New York (State). Legislature. Senate. Standing Committee on Banks
- Subject Files, 1963-1969; Undated; 1; 9.75 cu. ft.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  Series 1, Subject Files, consists of the files Smith maintained between the years of 1965-1969.
  - "A New State Park Concept…Caumsett" (Publication), Undated (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Abortion, 1967 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Abortion, 1968 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Abortion Law, 1967 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 4-5)
  - Abortion Law, 1968 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Abortion Law Publications, 1966-1968; Undated (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Abortion Law - Reports and Testimony, 1966-1967 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Abortion Law - Reports and Testimony, 1967 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Abortion Legislation, 1969 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 10-11)
  - Accountants Association, 1968 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Action, 1969 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Adoption Proceedings, 1966; 1968 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Advertising, 1969 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Advisory Committee on Intergovernmental Relations, 1968 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Agriculture, 1968 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Air Pollution, 1968 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Air Pollution, 1969 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Alcoholic Beverage Commission, 1965-1966 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - American Legion, 1969 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Anti-Poverty Bill, 1967 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Architects, 1969 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Atomic and Space Development Authority, 1968 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Atomic Power, 1969 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Attorney General, 1969 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Auto Mechanics, 1968 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Automobiles, 1968 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Automobile Club, 1969 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Automotive Shop Licensing Hearing, 1968 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Banks Committee, 1968 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Banking, 1967; Undated (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Bayville-Rye Bridge Project, 1966 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Belleayre Ski Area, 1969 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Bills, 1969 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Bills for Study, 1968 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Blaine Amendment, 1968 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Blind, Undated (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - BOCES, 1969 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Brain Injured, 1967 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Brentwood Public School District, 1969 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - Bridge Construction, 1967 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - Bridge Program, 1969 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - Brooklyn Polytechnic, 1969 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Budget, 1969 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Budget Message of Governor, 1969 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Bureau of Attendance, 1968 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Busing, 1969 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Campaign Guidelines, 1966 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Canners and Freezers Association, Inc., 1968 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Capital Punishment, 1968 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Central School District #5, 1968 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Centerport-Mill Pond, 1966 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Chiropractic Practice, 1969 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Church, 1968 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - City of New York, Undated (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Civil Practice Law, 1969 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Civil Rights, 1965-1966; 1968 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Civil Service, 1968 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Civil Service - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 17 -18)
  - Civil Service Employees Association, 1967 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Civil Service Law, 1969 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Civil Service - Memos and Reports, 1966-1968 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Clinical Laboratories, 1966 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Codes, 1969 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Codes - Correspondence File, 1968 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Codes - General Information, 1966-1967 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Codes - General Information, 1968 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 26-27)
  - Commack Library, 1969 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Committee on Health, 1966-1968 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Compulsory Health Insurance, 1968 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Compulsory Health Insurance, 1969 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Condemnation Procedures, 1969 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Condon-Waldin Law, 1966-1967 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Congratulatory Letters, 1968 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Congratulatory Letters, 1969 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Contractors, 1968 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Conservation - Bill of Rights, 1969 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Conservation - Snow Mobile, 1969 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - Conservative Party, 1969 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Constitutional Convention, 1965-1967 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Constitutional Reform, 1968 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - Construction and Contractors, 1968 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - Construction and Contractors, 1969 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - Consumer Problems, 1968 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 44)
  - Consumer Protection Bill, 1969 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 45)
  - Corporations, 1967-1968 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 46)
  - Corporation Laws, 1969 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 47)
  - County Law, 1968 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 48)
  - Crime, 1968 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Criminal Law, 1969 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Courts, 1968 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Courts, 1969 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Decentralization - Schools, 1968 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Deer Hunting, 1969 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Density-Sparcity Legislation, 1968 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Dental Society, 1968 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Disability, 1967-1968 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Disclosure Bill, 1968 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - District Attorney Bill, 1966-1967 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Divorce Law Revision, 1965-1966 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Division for Youth, 1969 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Door to Door Salesmen, 1968 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Drunken Driving, 1969 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Drugs, 1969 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Education, 1967-1968 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Education, 1968 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 18 - 24)
  - Education Bills, 1968 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Educational Conference Board Bill, 1968 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Educational Conference Board Bill, 1969 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Education Reports, 1968; Undated (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Education - Sex, 1969 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Education - State Aid To, 1969 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Engineering Legislation, 1969 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Eye Treatment Center, 1967 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Falconry Bill, 1969 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - False and Scurrilous Campaign Literature, 1966 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Family Court Act, 1968 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Fiduciary Committee, 1969 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Firearms, 1968 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Firearms - Reports, 1968 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - Fire Island, 1969 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Finance, 1968 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Finance, 1969 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Fluoridation Bill, 1969 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Form Letters, 1969 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Funeral Directors, 1968 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Gas Bills, 1968 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - General Business Laws, 1968 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence, 1968 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - General Practitioner Bill, 1969 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Gooley Dam, 1969 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Government, 1969 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Governor's Message, 1968 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Governor's Messages - Approval/Veto, 1968 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Grand Juries, 1969 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Grange, 1967 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Gun Control Legislation, 1969 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Health, 1967 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Health, 1969 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Health Exam Program, 1968 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Hearing Bill, 1968 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Hearing Bill, 1969 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Highways, 1965-1968 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Highways, 1968 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Highways, 1969 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Highway Route 25A, 1966-1967 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - "HI-SPOTS from Capitol Hill" Associated Industries of New York, 1968 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Home Inspection Sales, 1968 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Home Rule Messages, 1967-1968 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Hospitals, 1969 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Horse Trails, 1969 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Home Solicitation Bill, 1969 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Housing and Urban Development, 1968 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Hudson River Valley Commission, 1968-1969 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Humane Slaughter, 1967-1968 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Huntington Performing Arts Foundation, 1968 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Huntington Township, 1969 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Hypnosis, 1966; Undated (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Inspection Fees, 1968 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - Insurance, 1968-1969 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Insurance Committee, 1968 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Insurance Plan, 1966-1968 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - Interior Designers, 1968 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - International Longshoremen's Association, 1968 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - Invitations, 1968 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 44)
  - Invitations, 1969 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 45)
  - Invitations - Current and Future, 1969 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 46)
  - Interest, 1969 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 47)
  - Jet Airport at Calverton, 1967-1968 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 48)
  - Judges, 1969 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 49)
  - Judiciary, 1969 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 50)
  - Judiciary Law, 1967 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 51)
  - Jurors, 1969 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 52)
  - Justice Court Records, 1966-1967 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 53)
  - Juvenile Crime, Undated (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 54)
  - "Kit Goes to the Dentist" (Requests), 1968 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 55)
  - La Guardia Airport, 1968 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 56)
  - Labor, 1966-1967 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 57)
  - Labor, 1969 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 58)
  - Landscape Design, 1969 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - League of Women Voters, 1968 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Legislators' Retirement Bill, 1968 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Legislative Suggestion, 1968 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Letters of Recommendation, 1968 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Letters of Recommendation, 1969 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Liberal Party, 1966 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Liberal Party, 1969 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Library Districts, 1966 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Licenses, 1969 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Liquor, 1968 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Liquor Dealers, 1969 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Lotteries, 1967 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Luther Johnson, 1969 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Long Island, 1966; 1968 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Long Island Lighting Company Employees, 1968 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Long Island Railroad, 1969 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Malicious Telephone Calls, 1968 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Malpractice, 1968 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Marriage Counselors, 1968 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Mass Transportation, 1968 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Mass Transportation, 1969 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Mass Transportation Authority, 1967-1968 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Mass Transportation - Reports and Publications, 1967-1968 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Matrimony File, 1968 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Meat Inspection Bill, 1968 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Medcalf-Hatch Act, 1969 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 27-28)
  - Medicaid, 1967-1968 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 29-30)
  - Medicaid, 1968 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Medicaid, 1969 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Medicine, 1969 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Mental Health, 1965-1968 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Mental Health, 1969 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Mental Retardation, 1966-1968 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Mental Retardation, 1968 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 37-38)
  - Mentally Retarded - Suffolk Schools, 1968 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Metropolitan Transportation Authority, 1969 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Migrant Labor, 1968 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - Migrant Labor File, 1968-1969 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - Minimum Salary, 1968 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - Model Rocketry, 1969 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 44)
  - Mortgages, 1968 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 45)
  - Motor Vehicle, 1965-1966; 1968 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Motor Vehicles and Traffic and Highway Safety, 1968 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Mourning Doves, 1969 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - MTA Transportation, 1967-1968 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Narcotics, 1966 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 5-6)
  - Narcotics, 1969 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Narcotics Rehabilitation, 1968 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Narcotics Training: Working Notes and Bills as Introduced, 1967-1968 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Nassau County Water Authority, 1969 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Nassau County Water Bill, 1967 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - National Council on Crime and Delinquency, 1966; Undated (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Navigation Law, 1968 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - New York City School Decentralization - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - New York City School Decentralization - Reports, 1969 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - New York Racing Association, Inc., 1966-1967 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - New York State Lottery, 1969 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - New York Telephone, 1968 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Nuclear Power Plant, 1969 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Nurserymen Land Surveyor, 1968 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Nursing, 1969 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Nursing Homes, 1968 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Nursing Homes, 1969 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Nursing Profession, 1968 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Omnibus Teacher Bill, 1969 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - One Year Residency Bill, 1969 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Operational Grant - Title III, 1968 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Optometric, 1968 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Outdoor Advertising Bill, 1969 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Optometry, 1969 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Orthopedists, 1968 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Parental Responsibility Bill, 1965-1966 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Parental Responsibility Bill, 1969 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Peace Officer Status, 1969 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Penal Institutions - Bills Submitted, 1967 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Penal Institutions - General Information, 1967; Undated (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Penal Law, 1965-1966 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Penal Law, 1968 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 38-39)
  - Penal Law, 1969 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Penal Law - Law Revision, 1967-1968 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - Pensions, 1969 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - Pension Bills, 1968 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - Pension Fund, 1968 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 44)
  - Personal, 1968 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 45-46)